Guide to the Jeremy Ayers Papers MSS.610
Fales Library and Special Collections
Jeremy Ayers Papers
1919-2018
1980-2016
Fales Library and Special Collections
Ayers, Jeremy
Nelson, Daniel
Holton, Sandra
MSS.610
20.17 Linear Feet in 33 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 4 oversized flat boxes, 1 cassette box, 4 flat file folders, 2 card boxes, 1 CD box, and 1 LP box
116.86 Gigabytes in 19,281 digital files
6 VHS
3 Sound_Disc--Vinyl
27 Hi8
1 film reels
Jeremy Ayers (1948-2016) was a visual artist, writer, musician, photographer, and member of the Athens, Georgia creative community. The Jeremy Ayers Papers (inclusive dates 1919-2018; bulk dates 1980-2016) consists of materials created and collected by Ayers documenting his personal life and artistic pursuits as a visual artist, writer, photographer, and musician. Materials documenting Ayers' photography are both personal and artistic in nature and include photographic prints, negatives, slides, and large format prints for exhibitions. The collection also includes Ayers' journals, screenplays, manuscript drafts, loose notes, and notebooks with written prose and song lyrics; personal correspondence; drawings and sketches; and ephemera. Materials in this collection are in paper, analog audiovisual, and electronic format.
Biographical Note
Jeremy Ayers (1948-2016) was an artist, writer, musician, photographer, and member of the Athens, Georgia creative community. Ayers was born in South Carolina to Dr. Robert Ayers, a scholar of world religions and founder of the University of Georgia's Religious Studies and Philosophy Departments, and Mary Frances Ayers. In 1969, Ayers received his Bachelor degrees in visual arts and English literature from the University of Georgia in Athens. After graduation, he moved to New York City to pursue an MFA at the Pratt Institute.
In the 1970s, Ayers became involved in Andy Warhol's Factory, adopting the alter ego "Sylvia Thinn." As Thinn, Ayers wrote a column called "Why Not?" in Interview magazine. He also appeared in stage productions and performance art pieces as Sylvia Thinn. In 1973, Ayers sustained a severe traumatic head injury and shortly thereafter began suffering occasional seizures, which continued throughout his life. The persistent nature of his medical condition resulted in Ayers moving back to Athens, where his family still lived, but he made frequent extended visits to New York City.
Once back in Athens, Ayers became actively involved in the local arts and music scene as a songwriter, illustrator, graphic artist, and photographer. It was during this time that he collaborated with the musical bands the B-52s, co-writing their hit song "52 Girls," as well as lyrics for several R.E.M. songs. He also utilized his talents as an illustrator and graphic artist to create designs and images for the album covers of Athens musicians. During this time, Ayers also became a founding member of the underground band Limbo District. In addition to these collaborations, Ayers continued to write his own poetry, novels, and screenplays. Ayers remained an active artist until his death in 2016.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series and and four subseries.
Series I: Visual Arts
Subseries I.A: Photography
Subseries I.B: Video
Subseries I.C: Audio
Subseries I.D: Artwork
Series II: Writings
Series III: Personal Materials
Within each series, materials are arranged alphabetically by subject, name, or format. Untitled journals in Series II are further arranged in chronological order.
Scope and Contents
The Jeremy Ayers Papers (inclusive dates 1919-2018; bulk dates 1980-2016) consists of materials created and collected by Ayers documenting his personal life and artistic pursuits as a visual artist, writer, photographer, and musician. Materials in this collection are in paper, analog audiovisual, and electronic format.
Series I focuses on Ayers' visual art and is composed of photographs, video, audio, and artwork. Photographic themes include candid photographs of friends, travels, and daily life; his family including his father, Robert Ayers, and partner Daniel Nelson; his time as a member of Andy Warhol's Factory; artistic projects with props and staged poses; well-known individuals including R.E.M. singer Michael Stipe, B-52s singers Cindy Wilson and Kate Pierson, activist MaVynee Betsch, and singer Patti Smith; nature, animals, and landscapes; and the Occupy Wall Street movement. The video projects contain footage shot by Ayers documenting the life and culture of Athens, Georgia; footage of Ayers reading his written works; artistic projects; and the short film Carnival, which was a collaboration between Limbo District and local Athens filmmaker James Herbert. The audio found in this series was either created by Ayers or was affiliated with him. The artwork found in this series was created by Ayers and consists of pen and ink drawings; sketches; photographs of the artwork; photocopies; paintings; and collages.
In addition to being a visual artist, Ayers was a writer and lyricist, and this is reflected in Series II. This series contains Ayers' original writings including screenplays, manuscript drafts, and loose handwritten notes; as well as notebooks with written prose and song lyrics. This series also contains his journals, dated from the mid-1970s through 2014, which document his daily life, his thoughts, and sometimes include creative pieces.
Series III focuses on Jeremy Ayers as an individual and contains items relating to his personal life. Materials in this series include personal correspondence between Ayers and friends; archived Facebook posts; family photographs; and personal documents like his old passports, yoga certificates, and astrological readings. Ayers collected vintage photographs, postcards, stamps, and artwork by other artists – all of these are also included in this series.
In addition to paper and analog audiovisual materials, this collection also includes digital formats comprising of digital photographs, videos, audio, and computer files.
Researchers are advised that this collection contains a small number of photographs that include nudity. These photographs are identified in the folder inventory of Subseries I.A: Photographs with a content warning.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Daniel Nelson and Sandra Holton, the Ayers Estate, in March 2022. The accession number associated with this gift is 2022.020.
Custodial History
Glenn Horowitz Booksellers had attempted to broker a sale of this collection, but were unable to, and so the estate reclaimed and donated the collection to NYU. Before arriving at NYU, materials were moved from the Horowitz offices to another storage unit.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Appraisal
At the time of accessioning, the following items were appraised out of the collection: a package of morning glory seeds, two computer system start-up disks, a box of candy, a clipboard, 12 VHS and 1 Hi8 cassettes with evidence of mold damage.
During processing, the following items were appraised out of the collection: a deck of playing cards labeled "Male Nudes by Hollywood," a back pain booklet, commercially sold road maps, bank statements, two copies of Harper's Magazine, and Xerox copies of published articles and clippings. 625 RAW camera files were also deaccessioned at this time, while the jpeg files were preserved.
Athens (Ga.); Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Photographers -- United States.; Musicians -- United States; Artists.; New York (N.Y.).; Journals.; Screenplays; Postcards.; Correspondence.; Video recordings.; Photographs.; Digital images.; Drawings, pen and ink.; Sketchbooks.; Digital audio tapes.; Japan.; Costa Rica.; Italy; Florida.; Nelson, Daniel; Holton, Sandra; Andy Warhol Factory (New York, N.Y.); R.E.M. (Musical group); Stipe, Michael, 1960-; Wilson, Cindy, 1957-; Pierson, Kate; Betsch, MaVynee, 1935-2005; Smith, Patti; B-52's (Musical group); Ayers, Robert H. (Robert Hyman), 1918-; Limbo District; Herbert, James
- Series I: Visual Arts, 1923-2017; 1990-2016; 9.35 Linear Feet in 13 legal boxes, 1 flat box, 4 oversized flat boxes, 4 flat file folders, 1 cassette box, and a card box; 106.626 Gigabytes in 12,276 digital files
  Scope and Contents
  This series focuses on Jeremy Ayers' visual art projects and is composed of candid and professional photographs; video footage he shot or was featured in; audio associated with him; and examples of his artwork.
  Arrangement
  Materials in this series are divided into four subseries: Photography, Video, Audio, and Artwork.
  - Subseries I.A: Photography, 1970-2017; 1990-2016; 7.68 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 4 oversized flat boxes, 2 flat file folders, and a card box
    This subseries focuses on Jeremy Ayers as a photographer. The majority of the photographs in this subseries were taken by Ayers, but there are also photographs that feature Ayers, but were not taken by him. Ayers' photographs are both personal and artistic in nature and include photographic prints, negatives, and large format prints for exhibitions. Photographs in this series document Ayers' time with Andy Warhol's Factory and Ayers' alter ego "Sylvia Thinn"; the Occupy Wall Street movement; Ayers' everyday life and friendships; his family including his father Robert H. Ayers and partner Daniel Nelson; his travels to Japan, Costa Rica, Venice, Edisto Beach, and New York City; his former band, Limbo District; animals, nature, and landscape scenes; and notable individuals such as singer Patti Smith, R.E.M. singer Michael Stipe, B-52s singers Cindy Wilson and Kate Pierson, and activist MaVynee Betsch.
    This subseries also contains several examples of Ayers' artistic photographic series including his Magnifying Lens series, which features a magnifying lens held in different locations by various people and images distorted by placing the magnifying lens on top of the camera lens. This subseries also features his Oval Crystal series, which depict various people holding a necklace with an oval crystal in different locations.
    In addition to printed and digital photographs, the subseries contains copies of Ayers' published photography books: Aeronautica (2011), Today in New York (2011), and Occupy!: Photos from the First 6 Weeks of #OccupyWallStreet (2012).
    Researchers should be aware, for subjects and topics with both print and digital photographs, the digital files include a larger sample of photographs, including those that are printed.
    Materials in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by series names, personal names, events, publication titles, locations, and general topics.
    - Aeronautica (Photography Book), 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Andy Warhol's Factory and Sylvia Thinn, circa 1970s, 2017
      - Printed Photographs, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 4-7, Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Digital Photographs, 2017; FA_MSS_610_ER_5
    - Artistic and Posed, circa 1990-2000, 2013-2016
      CONTENT WARNING: These materials contain some nudity.
      - Printed Photographs, circa 1990-2000 (Box 34, Folder 1, Box 35, Box 36)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_6
    - Ayers, Jeremy, undated, 2007-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 9, Box 33, Folder 1-2)
      - Digital Photographs, 2007-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_14
    - Ayers, Jeremy and Daniel Nelson, 2001-2007 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Ayers, Jeremy and Friends, undated, 1963, 1977-1994, 2009-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated, 1963, 1977-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4-6, Box 3, Folder 1-2)
      - Digital Photographs, 2009-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_15
    - Ayers, Jeremy and Kate Pierson, 2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_16
    - Ayers, Jeremy -- Shadow, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_17
    - Ayers, Jeremy and Unidentified Woman, undated (Box 3, Folder 3, Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Ayers, Robert H., 2014-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Digital Photographs, 2014-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_39
    - Betsch, MaVynee, 1998, 2013
      - Printed Photographs, undated, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_23
    - Betsch, MaVynee and Kate Pierson, 2017; FA_MSS_610_ER_24
    - Christmas Celebrations, 2013-2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_8
    - Clowns, circa 1990-2000, 2007, 2012, 2016
      - Printed Photographs, circa 1990-2000 (Box 35, Folder 2, Box 36)
      - Digital Photographs, 2007, 2012, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_10
    - Dominique, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Give Back My Beast, 2012; FA_MSS_610_ER_7
    - Halloween, 2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_12
    - Horns Musicians, 2012, 2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Digital Photographs, 2012, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_13
    - KD's House, 2008; FA_MSS_610_ER_18
    - Limbo District, circa 1980s, 2017; FA_MSS_610_ER_19
    - List of Photographs by Jeremy Ayers, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Magnifying Lens Series, 2013-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 33, Folder 5, Box 34, Folder 4, Box 35, Folder 3, Box 36)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_21
    - Marching Band, undated, 2013
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_22
    - My American Dream Is... Series, 2012; FA_MSS_610_ER_30
    - Nature and Animals, circa 1990-2000, 2010-2016
      - Printed Photographs, circa 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 9-11, Box 4, Folder 1, Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Digital Photographs, 2010-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_31
    - Nelson, Daniel, 2007, 2011-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 34, Folder 3, Box 36)
      - Digital Photographs, 2007, 2011-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_11
    - Nudes, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Objects, 2010, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_32
    - Occupy!: Photos from the First 6 Weeks of #OccupyWallStreet (Photography Book), circa 2011 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Occupy Wall Street, 2011
      CONTENT WARNING: These materials contains some nudity.
      - Printed Photographs, 2011 (Box 35, Folder 4-5, Box 36, Folder 8-9, Flat-file-folder 1 Left, Flat-file-folder 2 Left)
      - Digital Photographs, 2011; FA_MSS_610_ER_33
    - Oval Crystal Series, 2013-2015
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 34, Folder 5, Box 35, Folder 6, Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013-2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_34
    - P!nk, 2012; FA_MSS_610_ER_35
    - People Wearing Animal Masks, undated, 2010, 2014
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Digital Photographs, 2010, 2014; FA_MSS_610_ER_37
    - River and Audrey, 2013-2015
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 34, Folder 6, Box 35, Folder 4-5)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013-2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_38
    - Sailor School Event, 2013
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_40
    - Scrapbook, undated, 1923, circa 1970s (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook, 2014; FA_MSS_610_ER_41
    - Smith, Patti, 2014
      - Printed Photographs, 2014 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Digital Photographs, 2014; FA_MSS_610_ER_36
    - Smithhaven, undated, 1981, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Stipe, Michael, 2010-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Digital Photographs, 2010-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_25
    - Stipe, Michael and Daniel Nelson, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_26
    - Stipe, Michael and Jeremy Ayers, undated, 2013
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_27
    - Stipe, Michael and Jeremy Ayers Outdoor Photography Posters, 2015-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_28
    - Stipe, Michael and Kate Pierson, 2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_29
    - Taylor Mead Memorial Service, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_42
    - Today in New York (Photography Book), circa 2010 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Travel -- American Beach, Florida, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Travel -- Asheville, North Carolina, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_43
    - Travel -- Costa Rica, 2014; FA_MSS_610_ER_44
    - Travel -- Edisto Beach, South Carolina, 2012; FA_MSS_610_ER_45
    - Travel -- Europe, undated, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5-8)
    - Travel -- Luck, North Carolina, 2012; FA_MSS_610_ER_20
    - Travel -- Japan, undated (Box 4, Folder 9, Box 5, Folder 1-4, Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Travel -- New York City, New York, 2010-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 5, Box 34, Folder 9, Box 35, Folder 8, Box 37, Folder 3-4)
      - Digital Photographs, 2010-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_46
    - Travel -- Unknown Beaches, 2013-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_47
    - Travel -- Venice, Italy, 2010; FA_MSS_610_ER_48
    - Undeveloped Film, undated (Box 40)
    - Unidentified People and Locations, 1970-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated, 1970-2003 (Box 6, Folder 1-6, Box 7, Box 8, Folder 1-7, Box 9, Folder 1-2)
      - Digital Photographs, 2010-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_49
    - Unidentified People and Locations (Oversized Materials), undated (Box 33, Folder 6-7, Box 35, Folder 9, Box 37, Folder 5-6)
    - Unidentified People and Locations (Negatives), undated (Box 9, Folder 3-6, Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Water Reflection Series, 2013
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_50
    - Wilson, Cindy and Band, 2015-2016
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Digital Photographs, 2015-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_9
    - Woman Walking Around New York City with Tree Branches Series, 2013
      - Printed Photographs, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Digital Photographs, 2013; FA_MSS_610_ER_51
  - Subseries I.B: Video, 1983-2016; 1990-2002; 1.21 Linear Feet in a manuscript box and a cassette box
    The majority of the video footage found in this subseries was shot by Jeremy Ayers and document the life and culture of Athens, Georgia. The videos also capture aspects of Ayers' everyday life and those who were part of his life. The short film Carnival, which was a collaboration between Limbo District and local Athens filmmaker James Herbert, is also found in this subseries. Materials in this subseries exist in a physical analog format and a digital format. Analog videos in this subseries have been listed with the original titles found on the tapes.
    Materials in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by original tape names, personal names, events, and general topics.
    - "2 60 Syd dream", circa 1990–2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0016)
    - "2 120", circa 1990–2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0004)
    - "April's dream of old ladies cued to rocking / cards/Olivia at party/D.B.M. at Atomic/July 4-Keith", circa 1990–2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0001)
    - "Angie/Tim/Kai –W. house/Cal + Ken on Swing / CAKE W. J. Ayers – 5433296", circa 1990–2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0003)
    - Ayers, Jeremy, 2013, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_55
    - Beach Vacation, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_52
    - "Bertha Ray #2", circa 1990–2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0017)
    - "Blood Unit / crickets/Bot garden/Bubbles / Aprils Farm / cued at end of bubbles after which some blank", circa 1990–2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0018)
    - "Brute - Good Morning Mr. Hard On", undated (Box 38, Vhs 610_0030)
    - Canray Poole Play, 2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_59
    - Carnival (Limbo District and James Herbert Productions), 1983 (Box 38, Vhs 610_0031, 610_0034)
    - "Caroline + Brent", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0013)
    - Christmas, 2015; FA_MSS_610_ER_53
    - "Coleman Barks Reading at the Bottleworks", 2001 (Box 38, Vhs 610_0033)
    - "Cued to Vic Chestnuts dream", circa 1990–2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0002)
    - "dreams of Corey Christian Kai", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0007)
    - "End good lense + flowers", undated (Box 39, Hi8 610_0026)
    - "ends w/lense over crickets at Bot Gardens / Cumberland Isle", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0019)
    - "Highlands", undated (Box 39, Hi8 610_0027)
    - "Highlands / Broken", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0025)
    - "Highland / ends", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0015)
    - "Jill Carnes dreams I stop the wind", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0005)
    - Magnifying Lens Series, 2013-2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_56
    - "MaVynee Interview, American Beach", 2001 (Box 38, Vhs 610_0032)
    - Nature and Animals, 2013, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_57
    - Nelson, Daniel, 2011-2014; FA_MSS_610_ER_54
    - New York City, 2011-2012; FA_MSS_610_ER_58
    - "Ollie cat + monarch B. / cued at Ollie after lots of space", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0009)
    - "Other + Bertha Ray #1", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0011)
    - "Silver Kabuki", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0020)
    - "Static", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0012)
    - "SWAMP", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0008)
    - "SWAMP / Highlands w/Elephant 6 / cued to dreams (1) Paul DeBoy (2) John Mitchell", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0014)
    - "Talk Re-Photo" (James Herbert), undated (Box 38, Vhs 610_0029)
    - "Tibetan Monks / Kilton offing mask", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0006)
    - "Tim Angie Kai in field", circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0021)
    - Unlabeled Super-8 Reel, undated; cuid41358 (Box Shared Fales 119, Super 8mm film reel 610_0028)
    - Untitled Tapes, circa 1990-2002 (Box 39, Hi8 610_0010, 610_0022-610_0024)
    - Video Notes, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.C: Audio, 1989-2016; 0.44 Linear Feet in a manuscript box
    Audio in this subseries was created either by Jeremy Ayers, as in the case of "Drums" and Ayers' interview with his father, Robert; created for Ayers, as in the case of "For Jeremy, Song of Bike Trip"; or created by groups that Ayers had a professional affiliation, as in the case of the R.E.M. vinyl discs. Materials in this series exist in a physical analog format and a digital format.
    Materials in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Drums, 2002; FA_MSS_610_ER_2
    - For Jeremy, Song of Bike Trip, undated; FA_MSS_610_ER_4
    - R.E.M. Christmas '89 Vinyl Disc, 1989 (Box 38, Sound disc--vinyl 610_0029-610_0030)
    - Robert Ayers, 2016; FA_MSS_610_ER_3
  - Subseries I.D: Artwork, 1980-2017; 1980-2000; 3.30 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 2 oversized flat boxes, and a flat file folder
    The artwork found in this subseries consists of Jeremy Ayers' pen and ink drawings; and sketches of people, original creatures, and designs. This subseries contains a sketchbook; photocopies of artwork; photographs of Ayers' artwork; transparencies; loose pieces of sketches and drawings; and collages like the one featured in the "R.E.M. Pageantry: What Noisy Cats We Are" tour program.
    Materials in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by format.
    - Artwork and Sketches, circa 1980-2000 (Box 31, Folder 7-9, Box 33, Folder 8, Box 35, Folder 10-11, Box 37, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 1 right, Flat-file-folder 2 Right)